<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/xsl/guide.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE guide SYSTEM "/dtd/guide.dtd">
<guide type="newsletter" link="20050606-newsletter.xml" lang="en">
<title>Gentoo Weekly Newsletter</title>
<subtitle>June 6th, 2005</subtitle>
<author title="Editor">
  <mail link="plate@gentoo.org">Ulrich Plate</mail>
</author>
<author title="Author">
  <mail link="patrick@gentoo.org">Patrick Lauer</mail>
</author>
<author title="Author">
  <mail link="fmonero@opensistemas.com">Fernando Monero</mail>
</author>
<author title="Author">
  <mail link="cherry@trombik.mine.nu">Tomoyuki Sakurai</mail>
</author>
<abstract>This is the Gentoo Weekly Newsletter for the week of 6 June 2005.</abstract>
<summary/>
<version>Volume 4, Issue 23</version>
<date>2005-06-06</date>
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo News</title>
<section>
<title>Python 2.4 to be unmasked</title>
<body>
<p>
Bryan Østergaard (see below for his portrait) announces that <c>python-2.4</c> will be 
unmasked on Wednesday, 8 June. It's been masked for a long time to allow for 
proper testing and bugfixing. The Python herd members are now confident that 
there are no major bugs left. Details of what's new in Python-2.4 can be found 
at the <uri link="http://www.python.org/doc/2.4/whatsnew/whatsnew24.html">official 
Python website</uri>.
</p>
<p>
Please note that only <path>~arch</path> users will be affected by the unmasking, 
and please remember to run the <c>python-updater</c> after updating Python to 
remerge all modules as neccessary.
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Busybox glitch contained</title>
<body>
<p>
As some of you may have noticed, the "rescue shell" was changed from <c>sash</c> to 
<c>busybox</c> a few days ago. This was motivated by the extra features and the 
extensibility of busybox, but on some systems it has lead to compile failures.
Since <c>busybox</c> is now part of "system", it was emerged on every update, so all 
users were potentially affected.
</p>
<p>
After some debugging the problem was identified as a bug in the stable toolchain related to 
the <path>nptl</path> and <path>nptlonly</path> USE flags which had been overlooked during
the original testing. It is triggered by <c>busybox</c> being built as a static binary -
if it isn't, it can't be used for recovery. This has been fixed now as far as we can tell.
Sorry for the inconvenience!
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Future zone</title>
<section>
<title>Gentoo for Zaurus</title>
<body>
<figure link="/images/gwn/20050606_zaurus.png"
short="Gentooforzaurus" 
caption="`emerge -B cpio` on a Sharp Zaurus" />

<p>
The <uri link="http://gentooforzaurus.opensistemas.com">Gentoo for Zaurus</uri> 
project is a port of Gentoo Linux and Portage in particular to the Zaurus 
family of PDAs from Japanese manufacturer Sharp. It is based on Anton 
Maslovsky's "cacko ROM", a replacement image for Sharp's own Linux 
implementation shipping with the various Zauri. <uri 
link="http://my-zaurus.narod.ru/">Cacko ROM</uri> tries to stay as close 
as possible to Sharp's original ROMs for maximum compatibility with the applications 
distributed by the manufacturer. Gentoo for Zaurus also makes use of the <uri 
link="http://emerde.freaknet.org/">Emerde project</uri>, offering a Portage 
port for Slackware and other distributions.
</p>

<p>
Gentoo for Zaurus can be mounted over NFS so no changes to a current 
configuration are needed. It includes a native <c>gcc</c> environment for ARM, 
the <c>zgcc-3.3.1</c> cross compiler for the main PC, and X11 for testing 
applications. Most importantly, Opensistemas has developed a tool called 
<c>tbz2ipk</c> that converts Gentoo binaries from <path>.tbz2</path> files to 
the Itsy Package management system format (<path>.ipk</path>) widely used on 
the Zaurus and other handhelds running Linux. Packages that have been compiled 
on Gentoo can thus be used on both Qtopia-based implementations such as Cacko 
or even the original Sharp ROMS, or more losely related alternative 
distributions like OpenZaurus.
</p>
<p>
The project was started in December 2003. Gentoo was chosen due to its
"compile all" nature (whcih helped a lot in porting), and because it seemed
like the right thing to do. Since compiling needs lots of space an NFS mount of 
external disks is usually needed, but the new Zaurus SL-C3000 (with a 4GB disk) 
could theoretically do everything locally. However, because the Zaurus is 
comparatively slow (featuring ARM Xscale processors currently maxing out at 
400Mhz) a <c>distcc</c> setup is preconfigured.
</p>
<p>
Opensistemas is providing hardware and people to support Gentoo/ARM
as well as they can. They anticipate a release of Gentoo for Zaurus sometime 
around July if nothing goes terribly wrong. Among the new features will be a 
2.6 kernel and a new <c>glibc</c>. Some additional documentation can be found 
at the <uri link="http://www.openembedded.org">OpenEmbedded website</uri> (the 
successor to the Openzaurus distribution). If all goes as planned most core 
packages should be working well near the end of the year, and maybe ARM will be a 
fully supported architecture in Gentoo again. 
</p>
<note>
The Spanish consultancy <uri link="http://www.opensistemas.org">Opensistemas</uri> 
recently announced a move to open the source of all their developments, not just 
Gentoo for Zaurus. CRM software SIC and proprietary modules for content 
management systems like OpenCMS and Typo3 will be placed under the GNU Public 
License, reports <uri link="http://www.diarioti.com/gate/n.php?id=8655">Diario TI</uri> 
(in Spanish).</note>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Developer of the week</title>
<section>
<title>"What I love most about Gentoo: the flexibility of Portage and the great community" -- Bryan Østergaard</title>
<body>
<figure link="/images/gwn/20050606_kloeri.jpg"
short="kloeri" 
caption="Bryan Østergaard aka kloeri" />

<p>
This week's featured dev is Bryan Østergaard, better known as <mail 
link="kloeri@gentoo.org">kloeri</mail>. Bryan is the organizer of Gentoo's 
monthly bugfix rally, the <uri link="http://bugday.gentoo.org">Bugday</uri>, 
and the maintainer of its website. Bugdays are organized each first Saturday
of a month, when users and developers gather in an IRC channel that has been
set aside for this purpose (<path>#gentoo-bugday</path> on 
<path>irc.freenode.net</path>), and spend the day tackling whatever problems 
have accumulated over the month. 
</p>
<p>
Bryan is also co-leader of the Gentoo/Alpha project, a member of the Python 
herd and the IA64 team that takes care of the Itanium architecture in Gentoo -- 
and he just got appointed to the role of Gentoo's Apache team leader. He manages 
to keep a healthy balance between maintaining ebuilds on his own, and enjoying 
lots of opportunities to meet new people on IRC during bugdays. 
</p>
<p>
After finishing Advanced Computer Studies in 1999 <mail 
link="kloeri@gentoo.org">kloeri</mail> has been self-employed, working mostly 
as a network and server administrator, but he also does security and 
development work when needed. Like most other featured devs before him, kloeri 
has not worked much on other OSS projects yet, but he enjoys improving Gentoo
(and especially Gentoo/Alpha). At the moment he lives in Denmark's capital 
Copenhagen.
</p>
<p>
As expected he uses an Alphaserver 800, but also two x86 laptops. These 
predominantly run things like <c>screen</c>, <c>irssi</c>, <c>vim</c>, 
<c>bash</c> and Portage. When he does use X (which is not so often) 
<c>enlightenment</c> is his preferred WM, but "there's not that much that text 
mode can't do", says Bryan. In the rare instances when he's not connected to 
his computers he enjoys cycling and watching movies with friends. Hardly 
surprising, as his motto is borrowed from Douglas Adams: "You live and learn. 
At any rate, you live."
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Społeczność Gentoo</title>
<section>
<title>Forum</title>
<body>
<p><b>Nowe pliki stage dla komputerów Cobalt Qube2/Raq2</b></p>
<p>Deweloper Gentoo <mail link="redhatter@gentoo.org">Stuart Longland</mail>
szuka "odważnych użytkowników", którzy przetestowaliby jego nowe paczki dla
architektur MIPS. Jeśli posiadasz komputer Cobalt Qube2 lub Raq2, oto gdzie
możesz go sprawdzić:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<uri link="http://forums.gentoo.org/viewtopic-t-343667.html">Gentoo Linux/MIPS for Cobalt -- Testers Needed </uri>
</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>gentoo-dev</title>
<body>
<p><b>Poszukiwania testerów</b></p>
<p>W niektórych paczkach dokonuje się zmian, które mogą spowodować ich
nieprawidłowe działanie. Aby zmniejszyć frustrację użytkowników, deweloperzy
potrzebują opinii w sprawie zachowania się nowych paczek - a gdzie lepiej
spytać, jeśli nie na liście mailowej deweloperów?</p>
<ul>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/28465">
dhcpcd-1.3.22_p4-r10 testing request </uri></li>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/28411">webapp-config
v1.11 - call for testers </uri></li>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/28317">
baselayout-1.11.12-r2 request for testers </uri></li>
</ul>


<p><b>Usuwanie paczek</b></p>
<p>W krótkim czasie pojawiło się kilka ostrzeżeń o usunięciu paczek, które
nie mają opiekuna, bądź są już nieaktualne:</p>
<ul>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/28395">[RIP] Last
rites for cinelerra. </uri></li>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/28438">Last
rites: nss-mysql </uri></li>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/28463">Last
rites: mail-filter/amavis </uri></li>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/28470">
media-sound/emu10k1 facing removal </uri></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Więcej spamu! Teraz o 30% mniej użytecznego!</b></p>
<p>Po poszukiwaniach deweloperów Debiana i innym spamie łowców głów z
ostatnich tygodni, w tym tygodniu mieliśmy okazję obejrzeć piękny przykład, jak
spammerzy zużywają coraz więcej zasobów, aby dotrzeć do coraz mniejszej
ilości osób. Ponieważ Gentoo już posiada forum, można się tylko zastanawiać
co motywuje ludzi do namawiania innych, aby dołączyli do jakiegoś nikomu
nie znanego "Forum Dyskusyjnego Usług Sieciowych"...</p>
<ul>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/28477">teh sp@m
</uri></li>
</ul>
</body></section>

</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo International</title>
<section>
<title>Japan: GentooJP Friday party fallout</title>
<body>
<p>
One retired and three active Gentoo developers, namely <mail link="nakano@gentoo.org">Masatomo 
Nakano</mail>, <mail link="matsuu@gentoo.org">Matsuu Takuto</mail>, <mail 
link="jstubbs@gentoo.org">Jason Stubbs</mail> and former dev <mail 
link="chriswhite@gentoo.org">Chris White</mail> joined  more than twenty 
other Gentooists for (American) food and drinks in Tokyo's Ginza district 
last Friday. The party was a subset of an annual Japanese "Open Source Party" 
where more than a hundred open-source developers and users gathered -- with 
one out of four attending the larger event already being a Gentooist.
</p>
<p>
At the private Gentoo party, the fan talk couldn't come to a timely end, so 
the party was ported to a second venue ("nijikai") in a Japanese pub. With 
the highly international crowd around the table, conversation was equally 
fluent in Japanese and English, centering around individual Gentoo stories, 
Japanese culture and various other topics.
</p>
<p>
Next time you happen to be in Japan, please let the GentooJP people know in 
advance! The Japanese Gentooists are always looking for good excuses to stage 
a party... Subscribe to the (Japanese) <path>gentoojp-misc@ml.gentoo.gr.jp</path> 
mailing list, more information to be found at the <uri 
link="http://www.gentoo.gr.jp/jpmain/about-gentoojp.xml#doc_chap4">GentooJP website</uri>.
</p>
<figure link="/images/gwn/20050606_nomikai.jpg"
short="GentooJP nomikai" 
caption="GentooJP drinking party in Tokyo" />
<note>Left to right: nakano (on visit from the UK), matsuu, mudrii (spearheading 
the Romanian gentoo.ro, but a local Tokyoite), Tomoyuki Sakurai (GentooJP and 
GWN lead translator for Japanese), Chris White visiting from California, and jstubbs, 
Australian living in Japan.</note>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Spain: "Massive Gentoo Install" in Lloret de Mar</title>
<body>
<p>
70 kilometres up the coast from Barcelona one of Spain's largest LAN 
parties is going to open its gates for the first time on 23 to 26 June 2005. 
<uri link="http://www.3lp.org">3LP</uri> is the cyberhome to this event
taking place in the town of Lloret de Mar on the Costa Brava. About
400 visitors are expected to get hooked up on roughly 4000 metres of CAT 5 
cable, to play games, of course, but also to participate in a 
net-installation fest of several Linux distributions, including a "massive" 
Gentoo stage3 install, according to the organizers. Applications for one of the 
remaining seats in the gym used for this event can be made via the 3LP website.</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo in the press</title>
<section>
<title>Newsforge (25 May 2005)</title>
<body>
<p>
Jem Matzan summarizes advice for users to help them down the stony road of tech
support at a hardware or software vendor's helpdesk, or <uri 
link=" http://business.newsforge.com/business/05/05/18/2033240.shtml?tid=3">"no-help 
desk"</uri>, as he prefers to call it. Matzan offers tips on how to 
prevent help desks from weasling out of a "supported platform" issue, and he 
explicitly condones lying to the support person if it serves your cause: "If 
you're asked to restart for Windows changes to take effect, wait a reasonable 
amount of time before telling them that the system has rebooted successfully." 
He recommends camouflaging your real environment also in those rare cases when 
a company indeed supports Linux, as this is usually only valid for officially 
supported distributions: "The same technique applies: you are using Red Hat 
Enterprise Linux 3 (or whatever is supported), not 64-bit Gentoo Linux or 
OpenBSD 3.7. Do not attempt to reason with support personnel."</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Moves, adds, and changes</title>
<section>
<title>Moves</title>
<body>
<p>
The following developers recently left the Gentoo team:
</p>
<ul>
<li><e>None this week</e></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Adds</title>
<body>
<p>
The following developers recently joined the Gentoo Linux team:
</p>
<ul>
<li>Colin Kingsley (tercel) - <c>mirrorselect</c>, miscellaneous ebuilds</li>
<li>Stuart Longland (redhatter) - MIPS</li>
<li>Kevin Quinn (kevquinn) - Hardened Gentoo</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Changes</title>
<body>
<p>The following developers recently changed roles within the
Gentoo Linux project:</p>
<ul>
<li>Bryan Østergaard (kloeri) - Apache lead</li>
<li>Aaron Walker (ka0ttic) - joined the recruiters</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo security</title>
<section>
<title>Binutils, elfutils: Buffer overflow</title>
<body>
<p>

Various utilities from the GNU Binutils and elfutils packages are
vulnerable to a heap based buffer overflow, potentially resulting in the
execution of arbitrary code.

</p>
<p>
For more information, please see the <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200506-01.xml">GLSA Announcement</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Bugzilla</title>
<section>
<title>Summary</title>
<body>
<ul>
	<li><uri link="#doc_chap1_sect2" >Statistics</uri></li>
	<li><uri link="#doc_chap1_sect3" >Closed bug ranking</uri></li>
	<li><uri link="#doc_chap1_sect4" >New bug rankings</uri></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>

<section>
<title>Statistics</title>
<body>
<p>
The Gentoo community uses Bugzilla (<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org" >bugs.gentoo.org</uri>) to record and track
bugs, notifications, suggestions and other interactions with the development team.  Between 29 May 2005 and 05 June 2005, activity
on the site has resulted in:
</p>
<ul>
	<li>729 new bugs during this period</li>
	<li>402 bugs closed or resolved during this period</li>
	<li>33 previously closed bugs were reopened this period</li>
</ul>
<p>
Of the 8477 currently open bugs: 88 are labeled 'blocker', 216 are labeled 'critical', and 610 are labeled 'major'.
</p>
</body>
</section>

<section>
<title>Closed bug rankings</title>
<body>
<p>
The developers and teams who have closed the most bugs during this period are:
</p>
<ul>
<li><mail link="base-system@gentoo.org" >Gentoo's Team for Core System packages</mail>, with 17
	<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-05-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-06-05&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=base-system@gentoo.org" >closed bugs</uri>
	</li>
<li><mail link="kde@gentoo.org" >Gentoo KDE team</mail>, with 16
	<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-05-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-06-05&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=kde@gentoo.org" >closed bugs</uri>
	</li>
<li><mail link="gnome@gentoo.org" >Gentoo Linux Gnome Desktop Team</mail>, with 16
	<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-05-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-06-05&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=gnome@gentoo.org" >closed bugs</uri>
	</li>
<li><mail link="web-apps@gentoo.org" >Gentoo Web Application Packages Maintainers</mail>, with 15
	<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-05-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-06-05&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=web-apps@gentoo.org" >closed bugs</uri>
	</li>
<li><mail link="swift@gentoo.org" >Sven Vermeulen</mail>, with 14
	<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-05-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-06-05&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=swift@gentoo.org" >closed bugs</uri>
	</li>
<li><mail link="printing@gentoo.org" >Printing Team</mail>, with 13
	<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-05-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-06-05&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=printing@gentoo.org" >closed bugs</uri>
	</li>
<li><mail link="net-p2p@gentoo.org" >Gentoo net-p2p team</mail>, with 13
	<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-05-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-06-05&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=net-p2p@gentoo.org" >closed bugs</uri>
	</li>
<li><mail link="neysx@gentoo.org" >Xavier Neys</mail>, with 12
	<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-05-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-06-05&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=neysx@gentoo.org" >closed bugs</uri>
	</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>

<section>
<title>New bug rankings</title>
<body>
<p>
The developers and teams who have been assigned the most new bugs during this period are:
</p>
<ul>
<li><mail link="sound@gentoo.org" >Gentoo Sound Team</mail>, with 17
	<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-05-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-06-05&amp;assigned_to=sound@gentoo.org" >new bugs</uri>
	</li>
<li><mail link="games@gentoo.org" >Gentoo Games</mail>, with 13
	<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-05-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-06-05&amp;assigned_to=games@gentoo.org" >new bugs</uri>
	</li>
<li><mail link="amd64@gentoo.org" >AMD64 Porting Team</mail>, with 13
	<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-05-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-06-05&amp;assigned_to=amd64@gentoo.org" >new bugs</uri>
	</li>
<li><mail link="media-video@gentoo.org" >media-video herd</mail>, with 12
	<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-05-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-06-05&amp;assigned_to=media-video@gentoo.org" >new bugs</uri>
	</li>
<li><mail link="kde@gentoo.org" >Gentoo KDE team</mail>, with 8
	<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-05-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-06-05&amp;assigned_to=kde@gentoo.org" >new bugs</uri>
	</li>
<li><mail link="java@gentoo.org" >Java team</mail>, with 8
	<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-05-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-06-05&amp;assigned_to=java@gentoo.org" >new bugs</uri>
	</li>
<li><mail link="base-system@gentoo.org" >Gentoo's Team for Core System packages</mail>, with 8
	<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-05-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-06-05&amp;assigned_to=base-system@gentoo.org" >new bugs</uri>
	</li>
<li><mail link="x11-drivers@gentoo.org" >X11 External Driver Maintainers</mail>, with 7
	<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-05-29&amp;chfieldto=2005-06-05&amp;assigned_to=x11-drivers@gentoo.org" >new bugs</uri>
	</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>GWN feedback</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>
Please send us your <mail link="gwn-feedback@gentoo.org">feedback</mail> and
help make the GWN better.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>GWN subscription information</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>
To subscribe to the Gentoo Weekly Newsletter, send a blank email to <mail
link="gentoo-gwn+subscribe@gentoo.org">gentoo-gwn+subscribe@gentoo.org</mail>.
</p>
<p>
To unsubscribe to the Gentoo Weekly Newsletter, send a blank email to <mail
  link="gentoo-gwn+unsubscribe@gentoo.org">gentoo-gwn+unsubscribe@gentoo.org</mail>
from the email address you are subscribed under.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Other languages</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>The Gentoo Weekly Newsletter is also available in the
following languages:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<uri link="/news/da/gwn/gwn.xml">Danish</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/nl/gwn/gwn.xml">Dutch</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/en/gwn/gwn.xml">English</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/de/gwn/gwn.xml">German</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/fr/gwn/gwn.xml">French</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/ja/gwn/gwn.xml">Japanese</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/it/gwn/gwn.xml">Italian</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/pl/gwn/gwn.xml">Polish</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/pt_br/gwn/gwn.xml">Portuguese (Brazil)</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/pt/gwn/gwn.xml">Portuguese (Portugal)</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/ru/gwn/gwn.xml">Russian</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/es/gwn/gwn.xml">Spanish</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/tr/gwn/gwn.xml">Turkish</uri>
</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
</guide>
