<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/xsl/guide.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE guide SYSTEM "/dtd/guide.dtd">
<guide type="newsletter" link="20050221-newsletter.xml" lang="pl">
<title>Gentoo Weekly Newsletter</title>
<subtitle>February 21st, 2005</subtitle>
<author title="Editor">
<mail link="plate@gentoo.org">Ulrich Plate</mail>
</author>
<author title="Author">
<mail link="fant@pobox.com">Andrew Fant</mail>
</author>
<author title="Author">
<mail link="degrenier@easyconnect.fr">Thomas de Grenier de Latour</mail>
</author>
<author title="Author">
<mail link="patrick@gentoo.org">Patrick Lauer</mail>
</author>
<abstract>This is the Gentoo Weekly Newsletter for the week of 21 February 2005.</abstract>
<summary/>
<version>Volume 4, Issue 8</version>
<date>2005-02-21</date>
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo News</title>
<section>
<title>Boston Linux World Expo: The Après-Show report</title>
<body>
<p>
The Linux World Conference and Exposition was held last week at the Hynes
Convention Center in Boston, Massachusetts, USA.  Gentoo Linux had a booth
in the .org pavilion, nestled between the friendly folks from Fedora and that
lovable lot from the Linux Terminal Server Project.  On display were an array
of systems demonstrating the wide array of architectures that Gentoo is
available for.  The main draw was clearly the diminutive Mac Mini with the big
cinema screen, brought by <mail link="dostrow@gentoo.org">Daniel Ostrow</mail>.  
Also present were Daniel's Sparc Ultra 60, several x86 laptops, and an AMD64 
and several embedded goodies brought by <mail link="vapier@gentoo.org">Mike 
Frysinger</mail>.
</p>  

<p>
A full team of volunteers helped staff the booth. Besides Mike and Daniel, 
<mail link="seemant@gentoo.org">Seemant Kulleen</mail>, <mail 
link="wolf31o2@gentoo.org">Chris Gianelloni</mail>, <mail link="absinthe@gentoo.org">Dylan 
Carlson</mail>, <mail link="jforman@gentoo.org">Jeffrey Forman</mail>, <mail 
link="latexer@gentoo.org">Peter Johanson</mail>, <mail link="lewk@gentoo.org">Luke 
Macken</mail> (lewk), <mail link="rajiv@gentoo.org">Rajiv Manglani</mail>, <mail 
link="fant@pobox.com">Andy Fant</mail>, <mail link="zx@gentoo.org">Chris 
Aniszczyk</mail> and <mail link="agriffis@gentoo.org">Aaron Griffis</mail> made 
appearances and helped out in the booth.
</p>
<figure link="/images/gwn/20050221_lwe.jpg"
	short="devs-in-a-row" 
	caption="Boston LWE Gentoo booth staff" />
<note>
Front, left to right: Andrew Fant, Chris Gianelloni, Mike Frysinger, Rajiv Manglani. 
Chris Aniszcszyk is leaning over the table just under the Gentoo poster, everybody else
are visitors.
</note>

<p>
Besides the perennial requests for CDs (which we had) and T-shirts (which we didn't),
there was a steady flow of interest in the PPC release, and a gratifying
number of comments by people who have come to realize that Gentoo has a
role to play in the enterprise.  Also of note was the forthcoming launch of a
<uri link="http://genux.org">Gentoo-based startup</uri> that will provide
custom binary packages to subscribing users through standard Portage mechanisms.  
A highlight of the week was the anti-bof, where 30-40 users and developers took 
over the top floor of the Globe Bar and Grill and got the chance to meet and 
mingle in person.
</p>

<p>
This was the first year that the LWE was held in Boston, instead of New York,
and by all accounts, it was a success.  There was a twenty percent increase in
vendor exhibits, and attendance was up by a similar amount.  It seems likely
that LWE will return again next winter, so start making plans for next year.
Thanks to everyone who helped to make our presence at the show a success.
For those on the west coast, LWE will be in San Francisco from 8 to 11 August. 
If you are interested in helping with the Gentoo booth at that meeting, please 
contact the PR team.
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Last call for FOSDEM</title>
<body>
<p>
More than 40 Gentoo developers, activists and power users have confirmed their
presence at this year's <uri link="http://dev.gentoo.org/~pylon/fosdem-2005.html">FOSDEM</uri> 
on 26 and 27 February in Brussels at the Université Libre de Bruxelles. The local
youth hostel has literally been taken over by the participants in the DevRoom
organised by Gentoo at Europe's largest open-source conference, and the schedule 
is packed with presentations by developers from all over Europe. Saturday night life
in Brussels will make it challenging to keep the tight schedule for the Gentoo developer
meeting on Sunday morning. 
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Free entrance to the Gentoo UK conference</title>
<body>
<p>
Thanks to securing sponsorships by the University of Salford and the London Internet 
Exchange, <uri link="http://www.linx.net">LINX</uri>, the <uri 
link="http://dev.gentoo.org/~stuart/2005/">Gentoo UK Conference</uri>, scheduled for 
12 March at Manchester's University of Salford, was able to drop the
entrance fee. Participants will now be admitted free of charge.
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Easy subscription to Gentoo RSS feeds</title>
<body>
<p>
<mail link="citizen428@gentoo.org">Michael Kohl</mail> has made <uri 
link="http://dev.gentoo.org/~citizen428/files/gentoo.opml">an OPML file</uri> available
that allows to automatically subscribe to three different RSS feeds from Gentoo at once, 
i.e. the Gentoo Linux news as published on the Gentoo website, the Gentoo Linux Security 
Announcements (GLSAs), and the feed for packages for x86. Many RSS-readers support
importing from an OPML file, making subscriptions easily manageable.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Future Zone</title>
<section>
<title>Gentooified Kuro-Box</title>
<body>

<p>The Kuro-Box is a toaster-sized PowerPC NAS (Network Attached Storage)
device designed for Linux hackers, owing at least part of its appeal to
the clever name: much better than its English translation of simply "black" 
already does, the "kuro" of the Kuro-Box hints at both the colour <e>and</e> 
the occultness of what may be lurking in the dark. Based 
on a <uri link="http://www.freescale.com/webapp/sps/site/prod_summary.jsp?code=MPC8241">
Freescale MPC8241</uri> (a 603e processor), it exists in two versions:</p>
<ul>
    <li>the original one, at 200MHz with 64MB RAM, a 100Mb ethernet 
        controler and one USB plug (around 160 USD without hard-drive)</li>
    <li>the HG version, at 266MHz with 128MB RAM, a 1Gb ethernet
        controler and two USB plugs (240 USD without hard-drive)</li>
</ul>
<p>
Obscured by the fact that it was spawned off Buffalo Technology's "LinkStation"
storage device series, it's probably the most inexpensive Linux/PPC development 
environment currently in the market.
</p>
<figure 
	link="/images/gwn/20050221_kurobox.jpg"
	short="Kuro-Box" 
	caption="Attaching a new meaning to network storage: 
	Buffalo's Kuro-Box"
/>

<p><uri link="http://penguinppc.org/embedded/kuro/">The history</uri> of
the Kuro-Box begins in Japan back in early 2004, when a Buffalo sister
company, Kurouto Shikou, decided to sell older LinkStation inventory
on the "power users" market. Thus, the oldest and biggest Kuro-Box hackers
community is Japanese, and the amount of documentation on
<uri link="http://linkstation.yi.org/">their Linkstation Wiki</uri> or on
<uri link="http://www.yamasita.jp/linkstation/">Yasunari Yamashita's
blog</uri> show how active it is. Since a few months, Kuro-Boxes are also 
distributed in the US and Europe by <uri link="http://www.revogear.com/">Revogear</uri>, 
and a new non-Japanese community centering around <uri
link="http://www.kurobox.com/forums/">a forum</uri> and <uri 
link="http://www.kurobox.com/online/">a wiki</uri> now has plenty of English
information available to them.</p>

<p>In both communities, there had been several attempts at replacing
the stock firmware with more generic Linux distributions ever since
the first Kuro-Box shipped about a year ago. The original firmware is too 
much NAS-oriented, i.e. only designed to be a file and printing server, 
whereas a complete Linux distribution would allow for easy experimentation 
and unlocking of the platform's full potential. Even setting up Gentoo systems 
inside the Kuro-Box had been tried before: <uri 
link="http://www.kurobox.com/forums/profile.php?mode=viewprofile&amp;u=48">jmgdean</uri> 
released a <uri link="http://www.kurobox.com/forums/viewtopic.php?t=111">Gentoo 
Total Conversion alpha1</uri>, and much work was done inside the Japanese 
community. However, all of those earlier attempts were mixed installations of Gentoo Linux on 
top of the original firmware: the toolchains were still based on gcc-2.95, many 
files were not managed by Portage, and there was still some non-free code inside. 

My <uri
link="http://www.kurobox.com/online/tiki-index.php?page=What+is+in+Gentoo+Beta1">beta1
release</uri>, on the other hand, is entirely built from sources, and exclusively 
via Portage. It is composed of:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>a stage3 image which can be installed directly on a fresh
        harddrive, and which completly replaces the original firmware</li>
    <li>a Portage overlay, with a few new or modified ebuilds</li>
    <li>a custom Portage profile, based on Gentoo PPC 2004.3</li>
    <li>many additional binary packages that should
    cover the most current needs for that kind of system</li>
</ul>
<p>
The installation process is mostly similar to "normal" Gentoo systems, except that
it begins in the so-called "EM mode" in which the box boots when it's not yet set up. 
This is a very minimalistic environment which can be accessed by both <c>ftp</c> and <c>telnet</c>. 
From there, you will be able to prepare your drive, <c>chroot</c>, and install the 
stage3 image. Then you switch the box to the "Normal mode", and hopefully it will
reboot using your fresh Gentoo system, which should be accessible by
<c>ssh</c>. Detailed instructions are available on a <uri 
link="http://www.kurobox.com/online/tiki-index.php?page=InstallGentooBeta1">
Wiki page</uri>.</p>
<p><b>Known limitation and future work</b></p>
<p>
The only thing that is not easily hackable is the content of the FlashROM, i.e.
the EM mode system and the kernel. The format of the flash image is well-known 
and documented (at least on some Japanese websites), but, as opposed to many other
Linux-based devices, there is absolutely no fallback in case of mistake once 
you've touched it -- a flashing error or a badly configured kernel will kill it
for good. Because of that, most users are still stuck to the original 2.4.17 
kernel, which is far from perfect. There are currently two directions 
explored to overcome this limitation:
</p>
<ul>
<li>
Installing a proper bootloader in the FlashROM: <uri link="http://www.kurobox.com/online/tiki-index.php?page=projectsBootloader">U-Boot</uri> 
would probably be the best choice, but this project is at too early a stage 
to give an estimate of its availability.
</li>
<li>
Dynamically replacing the running kernel. This has been made
possible thanks to <uri
link="http://www.kurobox.com/forums/viewtopic.php?t=277">jochang's
work</uri>, through the load of a simple kernel module.
Integrating that kernel switching in the boot process is the top
target for Gentoo beta2 (with everything it depends on, like a
proper packaging of kuro-ified kernel sources, etc.)
</li>
</ul>
<p>
Some other future work items include:
</p>
<ul>
    <li>improve the distribution system: in particular, use <c>rsync</c> instead
        of tarballs for overlay/profile</li>
    <li>by popular demand, add some meta-ebuilds for some common
        needs like "mail server" or "MacOSX-friendly server". Or
        release some kinds of customized "stage4"
</li>
<li>some minor improvements all around, like better LED status,
        maybe more precompiled modules for the stock kernel, etc.
</li>
    <li>maybe a (semi-)automatic installation process (from a LiveCD?):
        for some users, installing Gentoo by telnet on a Kuro Box is
        their first Linux experience, and it seems to be a bit too
        much at a time...</li>
</ul>

<note>Author Thomas de Grenier de Latour (TGL) is one of the Gentoo Forums
moderators, responsible for the French language forum. He will bring a 
Kuro-Box to FOSDEM in Brussels this coming weekend, if you would like to 
learn more about this little box or see it in action, make sure to stop by 
the Gentoo DevRoom.</note>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo security</title>
<section>
<title>PowerDNS: Denial of Service vulnerability</title>
<body>
<p>

    A vulnerability in PowerDNS could lead to a temporary Denial of Service.
  
</p>
<p>
For more information, please see the <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200502-15.xml">GLSA Announcement</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>ht://Dig: Cross-site scripting vulnerability</title>
<body>
<p>

    ht://Dig is vulnerable to cross-site scripting attacks.
  
</p>
<p>
For more information, please see the <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200502-16.xml">GLSA Announcement</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Opera: Multiple vulnerabilities</title>
<body>
<p>

    Opera is vulnerable to several vulnerabilities which could result in
    information disclosure and facilitate execution of arbitrary code.
  
</p>
<p>
For more information, please see the <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200502-17.xml">GLSA Announcement</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>VMware Workstation: Untrusted library search path</title>
<body>
<p>

    VMware may load shared libraries from an untrusted, world-writable
    directory, resulting in the execution of arbitrary code.
  
</p>
<p>
For more information, please see the <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200502-18.xml">GLSA Announcement</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>PostgreSQL: Buffer overflows in PL/PgSQL parser</title>
<body>
<p>

    PostgreSQL is vulnerable to several buffer overflows in the PL/PgSQL parser
    leading to execution of arbitrary code.
  
</p>
<p>
For more information, please see the <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200502-19.xml">GLSA Announcement</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Emacs, XEmacs: Format string vulnerabilities in movemail</title>
<body>
<p>

    The movemail utility shipped with Emacs and XEmacs contains several format
    string vulnerabilities, potentially leading to the execution of arbitrary
    code.
  
</p>
<p>
For more information, please see the <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200502-20.xml">GLSA Announcement</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>lighttpd: Script source disclosure</title>
<body>
<p>

    An attacker can trick lighttpd into revealing the source of scripts that
    should be executed as CGI or FastCGI applications.
  
</p>
<p>
For more information, please see the <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200502-21.xml">GLSA Announcement</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>wpa_supplicant: Buffer overflow vulnerability</title>
<body>
<p>

    wpa_supplicant contains a buffer overflow that could lead to a Denial of
    Service.
  
</p>
<p>
For more information, please see the <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200502-22.xml">GLSA Announcement</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>KStars: Buffer overflow in fliccd</title>
<body>
<p>

    KStars is vulnerable to a buffer overflow that could lead to arbitrary code
    execution with elevated privileges.
  
</p>
<p>
For more information, please see the <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200502-23.xml">GLSA Announcement</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Midnight Commander: Multiple vulnerabilities</title>
<body>
<p>

    Midnight Commander contains several format string errors, buffer overflows
    and one buffer underflow leading to execution of arbitrary code.
  
</p>
<p>
For more information, please see the <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200502-24.xml">GLSA Announcement</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Squid: Denial of Service through DNS responses</title>
<body>
<p>

    Squid contains a bug in the handling of certain DNS responses resulting in
    a Denial of Service.
  
</p>
<p>
For more information, please see the <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200502-25.xml">GLSA Announcement</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>GProFTPD: gprostats format string vulnerability</title>
<body>
<p>

    gprostats, distributed with GProFTPD, is vulnerable to a format string
    vulnerability, potentially leading to the execution of arbitrary code.
  
</p>
<p>
For more information, please see the <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200502-26.xml">GLSA Announcement</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>gFTP: Directory traversal vulnerability</title>
<body>
<p>

    gFTP is vulnerable to directory traversal attacks, possibly leading to the
    creation or overwriting of arbitrary files.
  
</p>
<p>
For more information, please see the <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200502-27.xml">GLSA Announcement</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Heard in the community</title>
<section>
<title>gentoo-dev</title>
<body>
<p><b>Using Gentoo in emulators</b></p>
<p>
After a failed install of Gentoo in MS VirtualPC, a user asks what
experiences others have with Gentoo in emulated environments. Read on
for a nice (win32-centric) collection of user experiences.
</p>
<ul>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/25480">Using
Gentoo in emulators</uri></li>
</ul>


<p><b>Portage performance improvements</b></p>
<p>
Another user found a bottleneck in Portage whose removal seems to reduce
startup times by at least 50%. Although that may be an extreme example,
it still shows that Portage performance is far from optimal.
</p>
<ul>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/25458">Portage
performance improvements</uri></li>
</ul>


<p><b>GLEP33: Eclass restructure</b></p>
<p>
After the large flamewars last time someone tried to change the way
eclasses are used and handled, <mail link="johnm@gentoo.org">John
Mylchreest</mail> and <mail link="ferringb@gentoo.org">Brian
Harring</mail> offer a new and quite comprehensive proposal. It can be
found at <uri>http://dev.gentoo.org/~johnm/files/glep33.txt</uri>
</p>
<ul>

<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/25427">GLEP
33: Eclass restructure</uri></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Runtime vs. devel packages</b></p>
<p>
<mail link="stuart@gentoo.org">Stuart Herbert</mail> offers some
thoughts on split ebuilds:
"For years now, RedHat have split a lot of their packages
into two sets ... a set containing what's needed at runtime to use the
package, and another 'devel' package containing header files etc which
are only needed for building software. One thing that it's really nice 
to do with a server is build it with no compilers etc installed.  The 
less that's on there, the less there is to maintain, upgrade, be reused 
by the black hats, etc etc." But, as it seems, there are also good 
reasons to do things "The Gentoo Way". Read on for a discussion of the 
pros and cons of both approaches.
</p>
<ul>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/25412">Runtime
vs. devel packages</uri></li>
</ul>

</body></section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo in the press</title>
<section>
<title>Security Focus (14 February 2005)</title>
<body>
<p>
After being talked about in a Security Focus article the week before, Gentoo 
developer and operational manager for the Gentoo Linux Security Team <mail 
link="koon@gentoo.org">Thierry Carrez</mail> now had his own column last
Monday: <uri link="http://www.securityfocus.com/columnists/299">"More advisories,
more security"</uri> is the title of his piece on the relationship between
activities in the security arms of Linux distributions and overall safety
for users. "Security advisories from a software publisher or packager should not 
be seen as bad news. There are always vulnerabilities in software, and when an 
advisory is released it means that one of these flaws has been identified and 
fixed," explains Thierry. "It also means the good guys have done their homework, 
and that one less flaw can be used by the bad guys to harm you."
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Linux Times (14 and 18 February 2005)</title>
<body>
<p>
A flamboyant installation report from Austria hit the online magazine 
Linux Times on Monday last week, under the heading "One week with 
Gentoo Linux." <uri 
link="http://www.linuxtimes.net/modules.php?name=News&amp;file=article&amp;sid=806">The 
article</uri> describes in detail an installation of Gentoo Linux
on slightly dated hardware, and tries to shatter the myth of Gentoo
being not easily accessible: "If there was a list of biggest GNU/Linux 
cliches, the statement 'Gentoo is hard to install' would be ranked 
among the top. Let me tell you a little secret: Gentoo is easy to install,"
says author Imre Kálomista, a student at Vienna University. And if that
wasn't enough, Gentoo again figures as a topic on Linux Times four days later
in a review of the Vidalinux release 1.1 in direct comparison to a "real"
Gentoo system. The <uri 
link="http://www.linuxtimes.net/modules.php?name=News&amp;file=article&amp;sid=831">article</uri>
concludes that the Puerto-Rican binary Gentoo clone strangely lacks binary
package support, but mentions a club membership for access to a repository
of precompiled packages.
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Cuddletech blog (12 February 2005)</title>
<body>
<p>
<uri link="http://www.cuddletech.com/blog/pivot/entry.php?id=82">Using Xorg 
6.8.2 &amp; Composite</uri> is the topic for Ben Rockwood's blog entry on
the new transparency features in Xorg, with a pleasant side note on the 
ease of installation in his Gentoo environment: "Thanks to Gentoo I simply 
yanked XFree86 (unmerge) and merged in Xorg 6.8.2." 
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Bugzilla</title>
<section>
<title>Summary</title>
<body>
     <ul>
          <li><uri link="#doc_chap1_sect2" >Statistics</uri></li>
          <li><uri link="#doc_chap1_sect3" >Closed bug ranking</uri></li>
	  <li><uri link="#doc_chap1_sect4" >New bug rankings</uri></li>
     </ul>
</body>
</section>

<section>
<title>Statistics</title>
<body>
     <p>
     The Gentoo community uses Bugzilla (<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org" >bugs.gentoo.org</uri>) to record and track
     bugs, notifications, suggestions and other interactions with the development team.  Between 13 February 2005 and 20 February 2005, activity
     on the site has resulted in:
     </p>
     <ul>
          <li>813 new bugs during this period</li>
	  <li>447 bugs closed or resolved during this period</li>
	  <li>20 previously closed bugs were reopened this period</li>
     </ul>
     <p>
     Of the 8040 currently open bugs: 101 are labeled 'blocker', 240 are labeled 'critical', and 596 are labeled 'major'.
     </p>
</body>
</section>

<section>
<title>Closed bug rankings</title>
<body>
     <p>
     The developers and teams who have closed the most bugs during this period are:
     </p>
     <ul>
<li><mail link="kde@gentoo.org" >Gentoo KDE team</mail>, with 25
              <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-02-13&amp;chfieldto=2005-02-20&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=kde@gentoo.org" >closed bugs</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="php-bugs@gentoo.org" >PHP Bugs</mail>, with 24
              <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-02-13&amp;chfieldto=2005-02-20&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=php-bugs@gentoo.org" >closed bugs</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="net-mail@gentoo.org" >Net-Mail Packages</mail>, with 21
              <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-02-13&amp;chfieldto=2005-02-20&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=net-mail@gentoo.org" >closed bugs</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="security@gentoo.org" >Gentoo Security</mail>, with 20
              <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-02-13&amp;chfieldto=2005-02-20&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=security@gentoo.org" >closed bugs</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="netmon@gentoo.org" >Netmon Herd</mail>, with 15
              <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-02-13&amp;chfieldto=2005-02-20&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=netmon@gentoo.org" >closed bugs</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="amd64@gentoo.org" >AMD64 Porting Team</mail>, with 15
              <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-02-13&amp;chfieldto=2005-02-20&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=amd64@gentoo.org" >closed bugs</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="sound@gentoo.org" >Gentoo Sound Team</mail>, with 11
              <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-02-13&amp;chfieldto=2005-02-20&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=sound@gentoo.org" >closed bugs</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="ppc@gentoo.org" >PPC Porters</mail>, with 11
              <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-02-13&amp;chfieldto=2005-02-20&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=ppc@gentoo.org" >closed bugs</uri>
            </li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>

<section>
<title>New bug rankings</title>
<body>
     <p>
     The developers and teams who have been assigned the most new bugs during this period are:
     </p>
     <ul>
<li><mail link="qmail-bugs@gentoo.org" >Qmail Team</mail>, with 54
              <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-02-13&amp;chfieldto=2005-02-20&amp;assigned_to=qmail-bugs@gentoo.org" >new bugs</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="sound@gentoo.org" >Gentoo Sound Team</mail>, with 23
              <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-02-13&amp;chfieldto=2005-02-20&amp;assigned_to=sound@gentoo.org" >new bugs</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="amd64@gentoo.org" >AMD64 Porting Team</mail>, with 19
              <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-02-13&amp;chfieldto=2005-02-20&amp;assigned_to=amd64@gentoo.org" >new bugs</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="media-video@gentoo.org" >media-video herd</mail>, with 17
              <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-02-13&amp;chfieldto=2005-02-20&amp;assigned_to=media-video@gentoo.org" >new bugs</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="kde@gentoo.org" >Gentoo KDE team</mail>, with 16
              <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-02-13&amp;chfieldto=2005-02-20&amp;assigned_to=kde@gentoo.org" >new bugs</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="sci@gentoo.org" >Gentoo Science Related Packages</mail>, with 10
              <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-02-13&amp;chfieldto=2005-02-20&amp;assigned_to=sci@gentoo.org" >new bugs</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="base-system@gentoo.org" >Gentoo's Team for Core System packages</mail>, with 10
              <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-02-13&amp;chfieldto=2005-02-20&amp;assigned_to=base-system@gentoo.org" >new bugs</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="x11@gentoo.org" >Gentoo X-windows packagers</mail>, with 9
              <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-02-13&amp;chfieldto=2005-02-20&amp;assigned_to=x11@gentoo.org" >new bugs</uri>
            </li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Moves, adds, and changes</title>
<section>
<title>Moves</title>
<body>
<p>
The following developers recently left the Gentoo team:
</p>
<ul>
<li>
<e>None this week</e>
</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Adds</title>
<body>
<p>
The following developers recently joined the Gentoo Linux team:
</p>
<ul>
<li>
David Gümbel (ganymede) - wine
</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Changes</title>
<body>
<p>The following developers recently changed roles within the
Gentoo Linux project:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<e>None this week</e>
</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Contribute to GWN</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>
Interested in contributing to the Gentoo Weekly Newsletter? Send us an <mail 
link="gwn-feedback@gentoo.org">email</mail>.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>GWN feedback</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>Please send us your <mail link="gwn-feedback@gentoo.org">feedback</mail> and 
help make the GWN better.</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>GWN subscription information</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>
To subscribe to the Gentoo Weekly Newsletter, send a blank email to <mail link="gentoo-gwn-subscribe@gentoo.org">gentoo-gwn-subscribe@gentoo.org</mail>.
</p>
<p>
To unsubscribe to the Gentoo Weekly Newsletter, send a blank email to <mail
link="gentoo-gwn-unsubscribe@gentoo.org">gentoo-gwn-unsubscribe@gentoo.org</mail>
from the email address you are subscribed under.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Other languages</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>The Gentoo Weekly Newsletter is also available in the
following languages:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<uri link="/news/da/gwn/gwn.xml">Danish</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/nl/gwn/gwn.xml">Dutch</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/en/gwn/gwn.xml">English</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/de/gwn/gwn.xml">German</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/fr/gwn/gwn.xml">french</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/ja/gwn/gwn.xml">japanese</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/it/gwn/gwn.xml">italian</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/pl/gwn/gwn.xml">polish</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/pt_br/gwn/gwn.xml">portuguese (brazil)</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/pt/gwn/gwn.xml">portuguese (portugal)</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/ru/gwn/gwn.xml">russian</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/es/gwn/gwn.xml">spanish</uri>
</li>
<li>
<uri link="/news/tr/gwn/gwn.xml">turkish</uri>
</li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
</guide>
