<?xml version='1.0' encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="/xsl/guide.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE guide SYSTEM "/dtd/guide.dtd">
<guide type="newsletter" link="20050117-newsletter.xml" lang="en">
<title>Gentoo Weekly Newsletter</title>
<subtitle>17 stycznia 2005</subtitle>
<author title="Redaktor naczelny"><mail link="plate@gentoo.org">Ulrich Plate</mail></author>
<author title="Redaktor"><mail link="bdowney@briandowney.net">Brian Downey</mail></author>
<author title="Redaktor"><mail link="ian@gentoo.org">Christian Hartmann</mail></author>
<author title="Redaktor"><mail link="patrick@gentoo.org">Patrick Lauer</mail></author>
<author title="Redaktor"><mail link="swift@gentoo.org">Sven Vermeulen</mail></author>
<author title="Tłumacz"><mail link="jbozanowski@gmail.com">Kuba Bożanowski</mail></author>
<author title="Tłumacz"><mail link="dziwisz@icslab.agh.edu.pl">Jakub Dziwisz</mail></author>
<author title="Tłumacz"><mail link="gooroo@gentoo.pl">Karol Góralski</mail></author>
<author title="Tłumacz"><mail link="lucass@gentoo.pl">Łukasz Strzygowski</mail></author>
<abstract>Gentoo Weekly Newsletter z 17 stycznia 2005.</abstract>
<summary></summary>
<version>Wolumin 4, numer 3</version>
<date>2005-01-17</date>

<chapter>
<title>Gentoo News</title>
<section>
<title>Gentoo name and logo usage guidelines</title>
<body>

<p>
As many might have noticed from last week's front page news item,
the Gentoo Foundation and Gentoo Technologies have drafted a document
on <uri link="/news/20050111-namelogo.xml">Gentoo name and logo usage</uri> 
containing legalese instructions when people and projects are allowed to use the
Gentoo name and/or logo. To make those as easily understandable as possible, 
here's a summary of the general ideas behind those guidelines.
</p>

<p>
The Gentoo trademark is described as follows:
</p>

<pre caption="Gentoo Trademark Description">
Computer software, namely operating system software that automatically
configures and optimizes performance on the underlying hardware and is adapted
for a large number of usage scenarios and applications, namely, secure servers,
development workstations, professional desktops, gaming systems and embedded
solutions.
</pre>

<p>
<uri link="/main/en/name-logo.xml#doc_chap4">Section 4</uri> and <uri
link="/main/en/name-logo.xml#doc_chap6">Section 6</uri> describe when
people and projects are allowed to use the Gentoo name in content that falls
under the description of the Gentoo trademark. These last words are very
important - when you use Gentoo in any meaning other than the description given
above, then this document does not apply to you. So you're free to talk about
the <uri link="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gentoo_Penguin">Gentoo penguin</uri>
or start an insurance company called "Gentoo Insurance".
</p>

<p>
So, when are you allowed to use "Gentoo" in a project or content that does
relate to operating system software (including the Gentoo operating system
specifically)?
</p>

<p>
We ask project managers not to call their project "Gentoo" or have "Gentoo" in 
its name. Otherwise users might get confused where to go for official
information, support or feedback. We also ask that, if you use "Gentoo" in any
other way (i.e. not within the name of a project) that still relates to
operating system software, that you clearly mention that Gentoo is a registered
trademark and that whatever you use "Gentoo" for is not part of the Gentoo
project and not directed or managed by the Gentoo project or the Gentoo 
Foundation. It is common practice to add a &#x2122; symbol behind "Gentoo" and
mention "Gentoo is a registered trademark of Gentoo Technologies, Inc." at the
end of your document. 
</p>

<p>
<e>Hold it! Does that mean we can't create a site that helps Gentoo users?</e>
Surely not, that's not our intention. The more Gentoo community sites we see, 
the happier we are. <uri link="/main/en/name-logo.xml#doc_chap6">Section 6</uri> 
grants explicit approval <e>to community sites</e> to use the "Gentoo" name in 
their project name if they acknowledge the "Gentoo" trademark and follow the 
conditions stated:
</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    Each page must clearly state that the site is not officially part of the
    Gentoo project. This informs their users that they should not try to get
    feedback or support from the Gentoo project about that project - chances are
    very likely that the Gentoo developers don't know how to deal with their
    requests.
  </li>
  <li>
    The website may not look like an official Gentoo website. The layout used by
    the Gentoo website (both the current and the upcoming new layout) are only to 
    be used by official Gentoo websites. Using the same (or a similar) layout might 
    confuse users about the origin of the website and where to go with feedback or
    comments.
  </li>
</ul>

<p>
So far about the Gentoo name. What about the "g" logo?
</p>

<p>
When you plan on using the Gentoo logo on a software/hardware product for 
<e>commercial</e> purposes, we ask you not to have the Gentoo logo as the <b>primary</b>, 
largest logo on the product. People who then use this product will know that the
product contains or is based on Gentoo, but that support and feedback should be
directed to you.
</p>

<p>
What about other products, such as merchandise? We currently deny any use of 
the Gentoo logo or artwork on such products <e>for commercial purposes</e>. The
foundation will grant approval to parties on a case-by-case basis to sell such
material, most likely to receive some funding from the sales, or to allow
projects that help Gentoo to fund their actions (such as conferences) with the
sales of these products.
</p>

<p>
You are free to use the Gentoo logo for any <e>non-commercial</e> purpose as long as
the logo is used to refer to the Gentoo project. For instance, you can use the
Gentoo logo to accompany an article about Gentoo, or on Gentoo LiveCDs you give 
away on conferences.
</p>

</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Brazilian Portuguese and Spanish translations, mailing list for German GWN installed</title>
<body>
<p>The new year started with excellent news for people in some non-English environments
who would like to read the GWN in their own language: Building on the success of the French,
Russian and Turkish GWN who re-emerge in the final days of last year, two other language 
versions were softly woken from their year-long sleep, and put up with fresh material to 
the Gentoo website:</p> 
<ul>
  <li>
    Marcelo Góes and Fernando Vaz have started the Brazilian Portuguese translation project 
    again, the first issue (<uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/news/br/gwn/20050110-newsletter.xml">10 
    January 2005</uri>) has been published just last week. They've requested additional help
    via <uri link="http://forums.gentoo.org/viewtopic.php?t=277628">a Forum thread</uri>, please join them if you can contribute!
  </li>
  <li>
    After an equally long silence, a team of Spanish translators has begun working on their 
    version, with the same <uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/news/es/gwn/20050110-newsletter.xml">10 
    January issue</uri> as their first being fresh out of the blocks, too, signed by five 
    initial collaborators (Demóstenes, Andrés Pereira, Víctor Argüelles, Miles Lubin and 
    Alexander Moreno).
  </li>
</ul>
<p>
A warm welcome to our new translator teams! If you would like to contribute to a GWN version 
in your own language, please send a short note to <mail link="gwn-feedback@gentoo.org">gwn-feedback@gentoo.org</mail>.
</p>
<note>We have received offers to translate the GWN to Esperanto, Basque, Romanian and other
languages. We'd love to let volunteers start working on those versions, but require a 
sufficient number of translators to be available in the first place. In order to provide 
a consistent service, at least three to five translators are recommended for each language.</note>

<p>Meanwhile, a long-standing request by readers of the German GWN has been answered. On top of 
being available at the official Gentoo website, the German version will be delivered to subscribers 
of a mailing list set up last week. Distribution will start from the current issue, if you would
like to subscribe, send a message to <mail link="gentoo-gwn-de-subscribe@gentoo.org">gentoo-gwn-de-subscribe@gentoo.org</mail> and follow instructions.</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Future zone</title>
<section>
<title>Project goals for 2005</title>
<body>
<p>Continued from <uri link="/news/en/gwn/20050110-newsletter.xml#doc_chap2">last 
week's GWN</uri>, this section today keeps track of more goals set forth for 
some Gentoo projects again. After Release Engineering, Kernel, and Gentoo/BSD 
defined their goals last week, here's what else is on the agenda for the next
months: 
</p>
<p><b>Portage</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Stabilize portage-2.0</li>
<li>Finalize a plan for (CVS-)HEAD portage features</li>
<li>Roll out a useful API</li>
<li>Release new versions with extensive changes</li>
</ul>

<p><b>Web-app</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Improve turn-around time on responses to security bugs</li>
<li>Publish a Gentoo webserver handbook (in progress)</li>
<li>Release webapp-config v2, and vhost-config v1 (in progress)</li>
<li>Remove webapp-apache.eclass from Portage</li>
<li>Find more maintainers for our packages</li>
</ul>

<p><b>Documentation project</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Pull in developers/contributors: contributors for non-x86, contributors for Gentoo projects, maintainers for existing documentation</li>
<li>Reintroduce status updates for all team members</li>
<li>Improve documentation on GuideXML</li>
<li>"Writing Style" documentation</li>
<li>Audit the existing documentation</li>
<li>More USE-case documentation (e.g. "Virtual Mailhosting Guide")</li>
<li>Documentation project update</li>
</ul>

<p><b>Forensics Herd</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Include more packages</li>
<li>Develop a bootable CD for network and disk forensic tools</li>
</ul>

<p><b>Embedded</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Include more packages</li>
<li>Solve bugs related to packages</li>
</ul>

<p><b>Netmon</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Catch up on bugs</li>
<li>Recruit more people</li>
<li>Integrate gentoo-security announcements and nessus</li>
</ul>

<p><b>Managers' meetings</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Rotate schedules across timezones so that more developers may participate</li>
<li>Discuss usefulness of these meetings and implement needed changes</li>
<li>Assign task to get logs put up on the web</li>
</ul>

<p><b>GLEPs</b></p>
<ul>
<li>Possibly recruit another GLEP editor</li>
<li>Consider allowing plain-text GLEPs</li>
</ul>

</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Gentoo security</title>
<section>
<title>Dillo: Format string vulnerability</title>
<body>
<p>

    Dillo is vulnerable to a format string bug, which may result in the
    execution of arbitrary code.
  
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200501-11.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>TikiWiki: Arbitrary command execution</title>
<body>
<p>

    A bug in TikiWiki allows certain users to upload and execute malicious PHP
    scripts.
  
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200501-12.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>pdftohtml: Vulnerabilities in included Xpdf</title>
<body>
<p>

    pdftohtml includes vulnerable Xpdf code to handle PDF files, making it
    vulnerable to execution of arbitrary code upon converting a malicious PDF
    file.
  
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200501-13.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>mpg123: Buffer overflow</title>
<body>
<p>

    An attacker may be able to execute arbitrary code by way of specially
    crafted MP2 or MP3 files.
  
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200501-14.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>UnRTF: Buffer overflow</title>
<body>
<p>

    A buffer overflow in UnRTF allows an attacker to execute arbitrary code by
    way of a specially crafted RTF file.
  
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200501-15.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Konqueror: Java sandbox vulnerabilities</title>
<body>
<p>

    The Java sandbox environment in Konqueror can be bypassed to access
    arbitrary packages, allowing untrusted Java applets to perform unrestricted
    actions on the host system.
  
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200501-16.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>KPdf, KOffice: More vulnerabilities in included Xpdf</title>
<body>
<p>

    KPdf and KOffice both include vulnerable Xpdf code to handle PDF files,
    making them vulnerable to the execution of arbitrary code if a user is
    enticed to view a malicious PDF file.
  
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200501-17.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>KDE FTP KIOslave: Command injection</title>
<body>
<p>

    The FTP KIOslave contains a bug allowing users to execute arbitrary FTP
    commands.
  
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200501-18.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>imlib2: Buffer overflows in image decoding</title>
<body>
<p>

    Multiple overflows have been found in the imlib2 library image decoding
    routines, potentially allowing the execution of arbitrary code.
  
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200501-19.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>o3read: Buffer overflow during file conversion</title>
<body>
<p>

    A buffer overflow in o3read allows an attacker to execute arbitrary code by
    way of a specially crafted XML file.
  
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200501-20.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>HylaFAX: hfaxd unauthorized login vulnerability</title>
<body>
<p>

    HylaFAX is subject to a vulnerability in its username matching code,
    potentially allowing remote users to bypass access control lists.
  
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200501-21.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>poppassd_pam: Unauthorized password changing</title>
<body>
<p>

    poppassd_pam allows anyone to change any user's password without
    authenticating the user first.
  
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200501-22.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>Exim: Two buffer overflows</title>
<body>
<p>

    Buffer overflow vulnerabilities, which could lead to arbitrary code
    execution, have been found in the handling of IPv6 addresses as well as in
    the SPA authentication mechanism in Exim.
  
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200501-23.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>tnftp: Arbitrary file overwriting</title>
<body>
<p>

    tnftp fails to validate filenames when downloading files, making it
    vulnerable to arbitrary file overwriting.
  
</p>
<p>
Więcej informacji można znaleźć w <uri link="/security/en/glsa/glsa-200501-24.xml">komunikacie GLSA</uri>
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Heard in the community</title>
<section>
<title>Web forums</title>
<body>
<p><b>Flurry of fits over GCC update</b></p>
<p>
GCC 3.3.5 was marked stable for <path>keyword="x86"</path> last week, but caused major uproar
because of highly unpleasant side-effects. The symptoms include errors when compiling some
libraries like Gtk+-2, which in turn lead to a few dozen duplicate bug reports in Bugzilla, 
and an equally frenetic activity in the Forums. The fix is simple enough, but people are still 
puzzled how something like this could have happened in the first place:</p>

<ul>
	<li><uri link="http://forums.gentoo.org/viewtopic.php?t=278673">Problems after upgrade gcc to 3.3.5 (solution)</uri></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>

<section>
<title>gentoo-user</title>
<body>
<p><b>Linux and TV tuner cards</b></p>
<p>
Linux supports various TV Tuner cards, but no one ever said it was trivial!  
This massive thread leads up our coverage of the gentoo-user list this week, 
and it involves a Gentoo user using a WinTV card.  Read this thread for an 
important lesson learned on using and configuring with <c>make menuconfig</c>!
</p>
<ul>
	<li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.user/114954">BT848 driver.</uri></li>
</ul>
<p><b>Soliciting initial advice</b></p>
<p>
Just about everyone has a few stories regarding their first installation of Gentoo.  
While Gentoo's install has undoubtedly improved by leaps and bounds over the past 
few years, Linux users migrating from other mainstream distributions like SuSE and 
Fedora are often intimidated with the "daunting" task of installing the operating 
system from source.  One potential Gentoo recruit solicited advice fom the list this 
week, with a handful of great tips in the tow.
</p>
<ul>
	<li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.user/114817">before beginning</uri></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>gentoo-dev</title>
<body>
<p><b>Encrypted root file system</b></p>
<p>
Paranoid? Trying to hide something? This thread gives you lots of good hints on encrypting even your root filesystem to keep your data away from bad people
</p>
<ul>
	<li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/24099">Encrypted root file system</uri></li>
</ul>


<p><b>Ideas for desktop TLP goals?</b></p>
<p><mail link="spyderous@gentoo.org">Donnie Berkholz</mail> asks "Where would you 
like to see the Gentoo desktop go? What's been done poorly, what's been done well?"
</p>
<ul>
<li><uri link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/23973">Ideas for desktop TLP goals?</uri></li>
</ul>


<p><b>2005.0 cleanups</b></p>
<p>
In preparation for the 2005.0 release, <mail link="vapier@gentoo.org">Mike Frysinger</mail> warns that some of the older profiles (2004.0 mostly) will be removed with the appearance of 2005.0. Please update your profiles!
</p>
<ul>
<li><uri
link="http://thread.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/24097">2005.0 spring cleanup</uri></li>
</ul>

</body></section>
</chapter>
<chapter> 
<title>Gentoo International</title> 
<section>
<title>USA: Gentoo booth at the Linux World Expo in Boston, MA (14 to 17 February)</title> 
<body>

<p>Preparations for Gentoo's presence from 14 to 17 lutego 2005 at the <uri link="http://www.linuxworldexpo.com/live/12/events/12BOS05A">Linux World Expo, Boston 
edition</uri>, are well under way. Architectures on display will include x86 and others, 
with a possibility of including a few MacMinis. There's <uri link="http://forums.gentoo.org/viewtopic.php?t=278336">a Forum thread</uri> for people 
looking for directions to the booth (and possibly to announce their intentions to visit
the show), and if you need help with accommodation or other tips, Bostonian <uri link="http://article.gmane.org/gmane.linux.gentoo.devel/24064">Andrew Fant</uri> has 
volunteered to serve as a local coordinator and pivot for informations.
</p>
</body>
</section>
<section>
<title>UK: Gentoo UK conference online registration open</title> 
<body>

<p>Online registration for the second Gentoo UK conference on 12 marca 2005 is now
possible via <uri link="http://dev.gentoo.org/~stuart/2005/">Stuart Herbert's web space</uri> at dev.gentoo.org. According to Stuart, there are even a few slots for presentations still
available to interested developers.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter> 
<title>Gentoo in the press</title> 
<section>
<title>Linux Format (Issue #62, January 2005)</title> 
<body>

<p>The UK based magazine's print version has an article on "the
ultimate distros". Ranking Gentoo 6th among 15 distributions under
scrutiny, their peculiar judgement of Gentoo including a not entirely 
satisfactory assessment of its usefulness has already triggered <uri link="http://forums.gentoo.org/viewtopic.php?t=280195">some 
repercussions in the Gentoo Forums</uri>.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Bugzilla</title>
<section>
<title>Spis treści</title>
<body>
<ul>
	<li><uri link="#doc_chap1_sect2" >Statystyki</uri></li>
	<li><uri link="#doc_chap1_sect3" >Zamknięte Bugi</uri></li>
	<li><uri link="#doc_chap1_sect4" >Nowe Bugi</uri></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>

<section>
<title>Statystyki</title>
<body>
<p>
Społeczność Gentoo używa Bugzilli (<uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/">bugs.gentoo.org</uri>) do
zgłaszania i śledzenia błędów, ogłoszeń, sugestii oraz innych form kontaktu z deweloperami.
Pomiędzy 09 stycznia 2005 a 16 stycznia 2005, aktywność w serwisie przedstawiała się następująco:
</p>
<ul>
	<li>zgłoszono 968 nowych bugów</li>
	<li>zamknięto lub rozwiązano 500 bugów</li>
	<li>31 uprzednio zamkniętych bugów zostało ponownie otwartych</li>
</ul>
<p>
	Spośród 7959 obecnie otwartych bugów: 116 oznaczono jako 'blocker', 229 jako 'critical', a 567 jako 'major'.
</p>
</body>
</section>

<section>
<title>Zamknięte Bugi</title>
<body>
     <p>
     Deweloperzy oraz zespoły, które zamknęły najwięcej bugów w minionym tygodniu, to:
     </p>
     <ul>
<li><mail link="amd64@gentoo.org" >AMD64 Porting Team</mail>, 40 <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-01-09&amp;chfieldto=2005-01-16&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=amd64@gentoo.org" >bugów</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="base-system@gentoo.org" >Gentoo's Team for Core System packages</mail>, 32 <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-01-09&amp;chfieldto=2005-01-16&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=base-system@gentoo.org" >bugów</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="security@gentoo.org" >Gentoo Security</mail>, 31 <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-01-09&amp;chfieldto=2005-01-16&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=security@gentoo.org" >bugów</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="kde@gentoo.org" >Gentoo KDE team</mail>, 19 <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-01-09&amp;chfieldto=2005-01-16&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=kde@gentoo.org" >bugów</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="eradicator@gentoo.org" >Jeremy Huddleston</mail>, 18 <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-01-09&amp;chfieldto=2005-01-16&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=eradicator@gentoo.org" >bugów</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="java@gentoo.org" >Java team</mail>, 16 <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-01-09&amp;chfieldto=2005-01-16&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=java@gentoo.org" >bugów</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="net-mail@gentoo.org" >Net-Mail Packages</mail>, 13 <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-01-09&amp;chfieldto=2005-01-16&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=net-mail@gentoo.org" >bugów</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="media-video@gentoo.org" >media-video herd</mail>, 12 <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=RESOLVED&amp;bug_status=CLOSED&amp;chfield=bug_status&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-01-09&amp;chfieldto=2005-01-16&amp;resolution=FIXED&amp;assigned_to=media-video@gentoo.org" >bugów</uri>
            </li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>

<section>
<title>Nowe Bugi</title>
<body>
     <p>
     Deweloperzy oraz zespoły, którym przypisano najwięcej nowych bugów w minionym tygodniu, to:
     </p>
     <ul>
<li><mail link="amd64@gentoo.org" >AMD64 Porting Team</mail>, 22 <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-01-09&amp;chfieldto=2005-01-16&amp;assigned_to=amd64@gentoo.org" >bugów</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="sound@gentoo.org" >Gentoo Sound Team</mail>, 18 <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-01-09&amp;chfieldto=2005-01-16&amp;assigned_to=sound@gentoo.org" >bugów</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="x11@gentoo.org" >Gentoo X-windows packagers</mail>, 15 <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-01-09&amp;chfieldto=2005-01-16&amp;assigned_to=x11@gentoo.org" >bugów</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="net-mail@gentoo.org" >Net-Mail Packages</mail>, 15 <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-01-09&amp;chfieldto=2005-01-16&amp;assigned_to=net-mail@gentoo.org" >bugów</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="kernel@gentoo.org" >Gentoo Kernel Bug Wranglers and Kernel Maintainers</mail>, 15 <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-01-09&amp;chfieldto=2005-01-16&amp;assigned_to=kernel@gentoo.org" >bugów</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="gnome@gentoo.org" >Gentoo Linux Gnome Desktop Team</mail>, 14 <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-01-09&amp;chfieldto=2005-01-16&amp;assigned_to=gnome@gentoo.org" >bugów</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="openoffice@gentoo.org" >OpenOffice Team</mail>, 12 <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-01-09&amp;chfieldto=2005-01-16&amp;assigned_to=openoffice@gentoo.org" >bugów</uri>
            </li>
<li><mail link="kde@gentoo.org" >Gentoo KDE team</mail>, 12 <uri link="http://bugs.gentoo.org/buglist.cgi?bug_status=NEW&amp;bug_status=ASSIGNED&amp;bug_status=REOPENED&amp;chfield=assigned_to&amp;chfieldfrom=2005-01-09&amp;chfieldto=2005-01-16&amp;assigned_to=kde@gentoo.org" >bugów</uri>
            </li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<chapter>
<title>Tips and tricks</title>
<section>
<title>Gentoo bugzilla search plugin for Firefox</title>
<body>
<p>Are you using the little search input field on the upper right of your Firefox browser
window? Most people do, and most of most people use it only to google for search terms. A
little lesser known is the possibility to add plugins for limited searches at specific 
websites - or the Gentoo bug report system, for that matter. This extremely useful little add-on 
was concocted by developer <mail link="vapier@gentoo.org">Mike Frysinger</mail>, and hunts 
for your search terms in the overview of bug reports at Gentoo's central Bugzilla.</p>
<pre caption="Download two files from the Mozilla searchplugin repository">
# wget http://mycroft.mozdev.org/plugins/Gentoo-Bugs.{src,png} 
</pre>
<p>Next, copy those files to the path where Firefox looks for plugins to use. Be root if you do this,
or prepend the following command with <c>sudo</c>: 
</p>
<pre caption="Install searchplugin in the appropriate directory">
# cp Gentoo-Bugs.src Gentoo-Bugs.png /usr/lib/MozillaFirefox/searchplugins/<comment>(or sudo if not done as root)</comment>
</pre> 

<p>
That's it. Kill any open Firefox windows, restart Firefox, there you go: Gentoo bug hunting 
at your fingertips. 
</p> 

</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Odeszli, przybyli, zmienili status</title>
	<section>
		<title>Odeszli</title>
		<body>
		<p>Następujący deweloperzy opuścili projekt Gentoo Linux w minionym tygodniu:</p>
		<ul>
			<li><e>nikt w tym tygodniu</e></li>
		</ul>
		</body>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Przybyli</title>
		<body>
		<p>Następujący deweloperzy przyłączyli się do projektu Gentoo Linux w minionym tygodniu:</p>
		<ul>
			<li>Kai Zimmermann (kzimmerm) - media-video</li>
		</ul>
		</body>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Zmienili status</title>
		<body>
		<p>Następujący deweloperzy zmienili w minionym tygodniu pełnioną w projekcie Gentoo Linux funkcję:</p>
		<ul>
			<li><e>nikt w tym tygodniu</e></li>
		</ul>
		</body>
	</section>
</chapter><chapter>
<title>Twój wkład w GWN</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>
	Jesteś zainteresowany współpracą w tworzeniu Gentoo Weekly Newsletter? 
	Wyślij nam <mail link="gwn-feedback@gentoo.org">e-mail</mail>.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<chapter>
<title>Opinie czytelników</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>
	Jeśli chcesz, aby ten magazyn był jeszcze lepszy, podziel się z 
	<mail link="gwn-feedback@gentoo.org">nami</mail> swoją opinią na jego temat.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>

<chapter>
<title>Lista dyskusyjna GWN</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>
	Aby zapisać się na listę dyskusyjną Gentoo Weekly Newsletter, wyślij pusty e-mail
	na adres <mail link="gentoo-gwn-subscribe@gentoo.org">gentoo-gwn-subscribe@gentoo.org</mail>.
</p>
<p>
	Aby się z niej wypisać, wyślij pusty e-mail na adres <mail
	link="gentoo-gwn-unsubscribe@gentoo.org">gentoo-gwn-unsubscribe@gentoo.org</mail>
	z konta, na które jest zasubskrybowana.
</p>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
<chapter>
<title>Inne języki</title>
<section>
<body>
<p>
	Gentoo Weekly Newsletter jest dostępny w następujących językach:
</p>

<ul>
	<li><uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/news/en/gwn/gwn.xml">angielskim</uri></li>
	<li><uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/news/da/gwn/gwn.xml">duńskim</uri></li>
	<li><uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/news/fr/gwn/gwn.xml">francuskim</uri></li>
	<li><uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/news/es/gwn/gwn.xml">hiszpańskim</uri></li>
	<li><uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/news/be/gwn/gwn.xml">holenderskim</uri></li>
	<li><uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/news/ja/gwn/gwn.xml">japońskim</uri></li>
	<li><uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/news/de/gwn/gwn.xml">niemieckim</uri></li>
	<li><uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/news/pl/gwn/gwn.xml">polskim</uri></li>
	<li><uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/news/br/gwn/gwn.xml">portugalskim (Brazylia)</uri></li>
	<li><uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/news/pt/gwn/gwn.xml">portugalskim (Portugalia)</uri></li>
	<li><uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/news/ru/gwn/gwn.xml">rosyjskim</uri></li>
	<li><uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/news/tr/gwn/gwn.xml">tureckim</uri></li>
	<li><uri link="http://www.gentoo.org/news/it/gwn/gwn.xml">włoskim</uri></li>
</ul>
</body>
</section>
</chapter>
</guide>
